DirectX Graphics Infrastructure (DXGI): Best Practices

Microsoft DirectX Graphics Infrastructure (DXGI) is a new subsystem that was 
introduced with Windows Vista that encapsulates some of the low-level tasks 
that are needed by Direct3D 10, 10.1, 11, and 11.1. From the perspective of 
a Direct3D 9 programmer, DXGI encompasses most of the code for enumeration, 
swap-chain creation, and presentation that previously was packed into the 
Direct3D 9 APIs. When you port an app to DXGI and Direct3D 10.x and Direct3D 
11.x, you need to take some considerations into account to ensure that the 
process runs smoothly. 

1)  Full-Screen Issues
In porting from Direct3D 9 to DXGI and to Direct3D 10.x or Direct3D 11.x, 
issues associated with moving from windowing to full-screen mode often may 
cause headaches for developers. The main problems arise because Direct3D 9 
applications, unlike DXGI applications, require a more hands-on approach to 
tracking window styles and window states. When the mode-changing code is 
ported to run on DXGI, it often causes unexpected behavior.
Often, Direct3D 9 applications handled the transition into full-screen mode 
by setting the resolution of the front buffer, forcing the device into 
full-screen exclusive mode, and then setting the back buffer resolutions to 
match. A separate path was used for changes to window size because they had 
to be managed from the window process whenever the application received a 
WM_SIZE message. 

DXGI attempts to simplify this approach by combining the two cases. For example, 
when the window border is dragged in windowed mode, the application receives a 
WM_SIZE message. DXGI intercepts this message and automatically resizes the 
front buffer. All that the application needs to do is call 
IDXGISwapChain::ResizeBuffers to resize the back buffer to the size that was 
passed as parameters in WM_SIZE. Similarly, when the application needs to switch 
between full-screen and windowed mode, the application can simply call 
IDXGISwapChain::SetFullscreenState. DXGI resizes the front buffer to match the 
newly selected full-screen mode, and it sends a WM_SIZE message to the 
application. The application again calls ResizeBuffers, just as it would if 
the window border was dragged.

The methodology of the preceding explanation follows a very particular path. 
DXGI set the full-screen resolution to the desktop resolution by default. 
Many applications, however, switch to a preferred full-screen resolution. 
In such a case, DXGI provides IDXGISwapChain::ResizeTarget. This should be 
called before calling SetFullscreenState. Although these methods can be called 
in the opposite order (SetFullscreenState first, followed by ResizeTarget), 
doing so causes an extra WM_SIZE message to be sent to the application. 
Doing so can also cause flickering, since DXGI could be forced to perform 
two mode changes. After calling SetFullscreenState, it is advisable to call 
ResizeTarget again with the RefreshRate member of DXGI_MODE_DESC zeroed out. 
This amounts to a no-operation instruction in DXGI, but it can avoid issues 
with the refresh rate, which are discussed next.

When in full-screen mode, the Desktop Window Manager (DWM) is disabled. 
DXGI can perform a flip to present the back buffer contents instead of doing 
a blit, which it would do in windowed mode. This performance gain can be undone, 
however, if certain requirements are not met. To ensure that DXGI does a flip 
instead of a blit, the front buffer and back buffer must be sized identically. 
If the application correctly handles its WM_SIZE messages, this should not be 
a problem. Also, the formats must be identical.

The problem for most applications is the refresh rate. The refresh rate that 
is specified in the call to ResizeTarget must be a refresh rate that is 
enumerated by the IDXGIOutput object that the swap chain is using. DXGI can 
automatically calculate this value if the application zeroes out the RefreshRate 
member of DXGI_MODE_DESC that is passed into ResizeTarget. It is important 
not to assume that certain refresh rates will always be supported and to simply 
hard-code a value. Often, developers choose 60 Hz as the refresh rate, not 
knowing that the enumerated refresh rate from the monitor is approximately 
60,000 / 1,001 Hz from the monitor. If the refresh rate does not match the 
expected refresh rate of 60, DXGI is forced to perform a blit in full-screen 
mode instead of a flip.

The last issue that developers often face is how to change full-screen 
resolutions while remaining in full-screen mode. Calling ResizeTarget and 
SetFullscreenState sometimes succeeds, but the full-screen resolution remains 
the desktop resolution. Also, developers may create a full-screen swap chain 
and give a specific resolution, only to find that DXGI defaults to the desktop 
resolution regardless of the numbers passed in. Unless otherwise instructed, 
DXGI defaults to the desktop resolution for full-screen swap chains. 

When creating a full-screen swap chain, the Flags member of the 
DXGI_SWAP_CHAIN_DESC structure must be set to 
DXGI_SWAP_CHAIN_FLAG_ALLOW_MODE_SWITCH to override DXGI's default behavior. 
This flag also can be passed to ResizeTarget to enable or disable this 
functionality dynamically.



// ==================
//    Git
// ==================
写完代码后，我们一般这样
git add . //添加所有文件
git commit -m "本功能全部完成"
 
执行完commit后，想撤回commit，怎么办？
 
这样凉拌：
git reset --soft HEAD^
 
这样就成功的撤销了你的commit, 注意，仅仅是撤回commit操作，您写的代码仍然保留。











